Contact

6063440594 (Mobile) tendoaki@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michaelmorris-00b4b7118 (LinkedIn) mmorris-sandbox.net/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

JavaScript
Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
PHP

Michael Morris

Senior Automated Test Developer Williamsburg, Kentucky, United States

Summary

I've been involved in professional web development for 19 years. I am a full stack capable developer, but much of my recent experience has been in the JavaScript sphere, particularly server side with Node.js. I have extensive experience with the emerging Single-Spa framework which allows multiple popular frameworks to be used on a website at the same time, or more importantly allows older websites to be divided up into discrete chunks allowing those chunks to be updated. I know and vastly prefer Typescript to vanilla JavaScript.

I am passionate about the BDD process which provides the most value to the client of all the various testing processes out there. I this delivery process to an entire team. I taught that team, around 30 strong, how to use Cucumber with Puppeteer (Google's antecedent to Microsoft Playwright) using binding shim I wrote for them, and then shepherded the development of nearly 1000 functional tests on a code base that was being developed without automated testing before. That testing system also included a data provider mock to decouple front end development from the back end team so the front end coders could do their work regardless if the back end team had the database servers up.

I am fully versed in the construction of deployment pipelines in gitlab, and have set up continuous integration tasks in Circle CI, Travis CI and Jenkins. I thoroughly test code, usually in Cucumber-js, but I'm also familiar with Jest (I've played with Mocha, Chai and Jasmine enough to know I can be up to speed with them quickly). I have used Ansible and constructed playbooks with it.

I know jQuery, Bootstrap, and even abandoned stuff like Prototype.js. I am well versed in the process of updating software from those projects to modern ES6+ frameworks.

I have worked on PHP extensively and I have contributor credits on the Drupal project and PHPUnit. I have worked with GoLang and C# over the years. I had a 2 year stint with Java writing Cucumber tests in the Java implementation of that framework. I've had to write Python scripts for AWS containers. Oh, yeah, and I have worked with those although not as much as I'd like to. There's very little I can't pick up quickly.

I know how to use Adobe Creative suite, Jira and participate in Agile methodology.

Outside code I play the piano and recorder flutes. Before moving to care for my parents I was active in musical theater in the Mobile AL area. I sing countertenor (highest male vocal range).

Experience

Freelance (Self employed)
Web Developer
January 2023 - Present (4 months)
Williamsburg, Kentucky, United States

Rural Sourcing Senior Software Developer January 2018 - January 2023 (5 years 1 month) Atlanta, Georgia, United States

FLEETCOR

Senior Web Developer August 2020 - December 2022 (2 years 5 months) Atlanta, Georgia, United States

Fleetcor was a client of Rural Sourcing and I was a consultant.

I introduced the entire production staff from Product owners down to Behavior Driven Development, altering the workflow of the entire company to create more accurate and meaningful estimates of development time based on a count of the scenarios and their steps rather than pure speculation.

Built the functional test layer of the application in Node.js using cucumber-JS and Puppeteer as browser driver.

Built a mocking engine in Express.js that could accurately simulate the responses of the REST API provided by the backend team in MuleSoft. Prior to this engine being introduced the front end teams (around 20 people) suffered multiple work stoppages when the dev REST API went down - which at worst was a weekly occurrence, usually when they tried to deploy something the first time.

Served as Interim lead application designer for two months. After the lead left the only other Go programmer left so I was left to maintain the deployment of the site and debug all issues the teams had with Go modules, and perform modifications on the deploy scripts as needed.

Once the new lead application designer was hired I implemented his decision to move the application away from a framework-less approach built on the Hugo static site generator to a React site. The new designer chose to use a micro-frontend architecture using the Single Spa framework, but left the details to me, so the following was done:

- Micro-frontends were to be built in Typescript. I had to lead multiple retraining classes in support of this.
- Each page of the site was to be moved to its own repository with its own production pipeline. I wrote all of the supporting CI scripts in GitLab for this and created all project templates to be used.

McKenney's, Inc. Web Developer February 2020 - March 2020 (2 months) Atlanta, Georgia, United States

This was a six week contract with RSI.

McKenney's provides HVAC and smart building optimization services for some of the largest structures in the Atlanta area. Some of these structures have in excess of 90,000 data points reporting every 15 minutes. They have a brilliant engineer on staff to gather and collate this information, and I was tasked to build a front end for him to make the information he'd gathered more accessible. This engagement was for six weeks.

The backend already in place was in MVC Razor. I learned how to get some templates and with a little guidance did what little C# code I needed to support the pages he needed. We chose to go with a combination of AgGrid to write

the reports, and CodeMirror to allow his team to write in their own report formulae into the application in Excel style. A custom multiselect tool was also developed to sort through the thousands of possible data points.

Enterprise
Automated QA Programmer
April 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 10 months)
St Louis, Missouri, United States

Contract position while at RSI. I wrote Cucumber end to end tests for an Angular application in Java.

Lexington-Fayette Urban County Government (LFUCG) Web Developer January 2017 - August 2017 (8 months)

Lexington, Kentucky, United States

I was charged with general maintenance and expansion of the city website using Drupal 8, including the addition of a parks map system using ArchGis.

The Tombras Group Web Developer July 2013 - August 2016 (3 years 2 months)

I built advertising focused sites using Wordpress and Drupal.

Webbed Sphere Inc.
Web Developer
June 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 1 month)
Corbin, Kentucky, United States

PHP, JavaScript and CSS work on a custom in house e-commerce solution. Attempted to migrate the site to Magento, but Magento could not be made to work with a catalog of around 6 million items.

eGovernment Solutions Web Developer May 2010 - April 2012 (2 years) Knoxville, Tennessee, United States

This company provides government support web applications for counties in the state of Tennessee, allowing citizens to pay fines and taxes online. The software had no automated tests at all, and it was at this time I began the process of learning automated tests to try to make the task more doable. The program was entirely in house and written to support IE 6. Weaning the

software from IE 6 only was high on the task list which led to one of the more interesting bits of code I ever wrote.

The software was not only an online portal, it was an in office management suite. The clients wanted one click printing of documents, which isn't possible in JavaScript because of hackers. However, by contract the physical server was to be placed in the office. I took advantage of this unusual arrangement of the server being on the same local network as the printers they wanted to print with and wrote a PHP LDAP library to drive the printing.

I also optimized many of the report queries. The most memorable was one that took 8 hours to run before I rewrote it to run in 4 minutes - three of which were spent on a temporary table creation query to copy the data over to something normalized.

Education

University of Kentucky Theater · (1996 - 2000)